Elloani Ross Pitogo

A diligent **software engineer** with demonstrated experience in front-end development using ReactJS for almost 4 years now. I'm skilled in other front-end technologies (HTML5, CSS3/SASS, JavaScript/ES6, Redux), version control (git, svn) and interaction with back-end systems through REST API. I'm currently learning TypeScript and Test Driven Development using Jest.

Cebu City, Philippines +639451220627 pelloani@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cloud Employee — Front-end ReactJS Developer

May 2021 - Present

- Working as a front-end web developer using ReactJS as main technology along with HTML5, CSS3 (with SASS) and JavaScript (ES6). I am directly reporting to a UK-based client's CTO and working as an extension of their development team building CRM-related web applications. I work closely with one other front-end engineer, UI/UX designers and back-end engineer which is also our CTO.
- In building layouts, we front-end engineers refer to the designs created by the UI/UX designers in Figma. We are in constant communication together with the back-end engineer to make sure that the designs are in-line with the data and that we give the best user experience to the users. We also build our own components which are created in a separate repository. These components are exported as a package and will be used by various applications which we also build and maintain

Advanced World Solutions, Inc. — Associate Research and Development Engineer

October 2020 - May 2021

- Maintaining a ReactJS web-based UI application for next generation MFP by resolving UI specific issues involving system redesign which are raised during QA done by onsite team. I'm one of the developers that lead a sub-team in resolving a specific category of UI issue. For issues involving system redesign, I'm the one creating a solution and proposal which is reviewed by my tech lead for submission and approval by the client.
- Got promoted two ranks higher from Assistant R&D Engineer.
 Normally from Assistant, one would transition to Senior
 Assistant first before achieving Associate.

SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3

SASS/SCSS

JavaScript (ES6)

ReactIS

Redux

Version Control (Git, SVN)

ACHIEVEMENTS/ CERTIFICATES

Computer Engineering Magna Cum Laude graduate

Philippine National IT Standards (**PhilNITS**) FE level certification

- Nov 2018 (No expiration)

Japanese Language
Proficiency Test (JLPT) N4
level certification

- Jan 2019 (No expiration)

LANGUAGES

English (Professional Proficiency)

Japanese (Limited Working Proficiency)

Advanced World Solutions, Inc. — Assistant Research and Development Engineer

July 2019 - October 2020

- Further developed my ReactJS and front-end skills through continuation of the next phases of development of a ReactJS web-based UI application for next generation MFP. I'm particularly assigned in the template team which is responsible for building and maintaining reusable components which will be used by other developers for the presentational parts of the system. I'm also assigned to resolve some technical issues raised by the Japanese client that concerns the entire system in general which required me to submit proposals subject to their approval.
- Got deployed onsite in Japan for 7 months to support the next phases of the application development which are needed to be done onsite (e.g. Integration testing, resolving issues that can only be performed onsite)

Advanced World Solutions, Inc. — Junior Research and Development Engineer

July 2018 - July 2019

- Underwent an extensive ACTION program which is basically a 5-month training program where I learned N4 level Nihongo, FE level computer concepts through PhilNITS course and various programming languages and technologies such as C, Java, JavaScript and ReactJS among others.
- Passed both Nihongo and PhilNITS standardized examinations and got both JLPT N4 and PhilNITS FE certification.
- Started my ReactJS career by being deployed to two projects involving the said technology: (1) Internal time accounting web application; (2) Web-based UI Panel application for next generation MFP (Multifunctional Printer).
- In the first few months of the MFP UI application development, my primary task was to port specific layers/screens and components of an existing system from Flash AS3 and xml technology to a much more modern ReactJS and HTML5 technology.

EDUCATION

University of San Carlos, Cebu City — Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

2013 - 2018

Graduated as Magna Cum Laude

I was immersed mainly in computer hardware, embedded systems and

low-level programming and as a matter of fact, my undergraduate thesis involves mainly embedded systems.. However during the last 2 years of my course, I started taking interest in software development and took Software Engineering as an elective. I have gained a lot of knowledge about Web Development (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, SQL) and Mobile Development (iOS Development through Objective-C) through various courses offered under Software Engineering.

St. Martin de Porres Academy, Daanbantayan, Cebu— *High School Degree*

2009 - 2013

Graduated as High School Valedictorian